hello okay so uh I want to take uh take
up uh one paper which is a very recent
paper it was presented at Coral and
there is a YouTube video for it and I
like this paper a lot uh I mean of
course I'm sure we can find holes in it
but uh it has it has various components
which I think are quite sensible of how
to do this so uh what I'm going to do is
uh I'll take you through this and uh
actually I'm going to uh just play Let
the video play because uh I don't need
to repeat a lecture
when okay so so what they do is they the
range of tasks is not as fancy okay it's
it's sort of more classical type
robotics people's tasks like you know
opening a drawer picking up an object
dropping in and so forth right so so
then list of tasks is not as exotic as
we saw in the Google demo or a demo
however what I like about it is that it
it does have generalization it has
generalization across objects which to
me is important and I think it has
robustness uh but for a much smaller set
of
tasks the hardware is not is not more
General it's still parallel geographer
so from that pers perspective my
complaints still apply it's slightly
different I think this is the the shuran
song version the
Umi uh which is slightly different it's
got like another camera so you get the
equivalent of a stereo View and uh I
mean that we won we don't need to go
into the that detail but it's a slightly
different hardware setup uh okay so uh
so uh so just to repeat what they say
they also connected to language models
in a fairly sensible way so you you use
the language models to to create a to
have a high level plan and then then you
have if you consider the components of
that plan those are going to be skills
right like pick up put down uh open the
drawer things like that so then that
becomes uh that you condition the policy
on that so so from the plan you get the
individual actions and then you the
policy is conditioned on on that on that
uh action which is very very
sensible okay so uh let's see if this uh
so I'm going to play this uh this I I
apologize that instead of giving a
lecture I'm letting you watch YouTube
but hi everyone my name is moral I'm a
PhD student at carneg melon and I'm very
excited to talk to you about our work on
building generalist agents for robotic
manipulation this was work done with my
co-lead minl collaborators at Apple and
of course my advisers at
CMU as a teaser I want to show you our
final result manip gen a single
generalist agent across manipulation
tasks this is a text conditioned agent
that performs zero shot long Horizon
manipulation we deployed on five
different tasks with a variety of
different setups which I show here
I really want to emphasize these tasks
are quite difficult much harder than
what you would see normally because
these scenes are extremely complex many
obstacles objects and
receptacles this single agent has to
perform Collision of voidance generalize
to arbitrary objects and perform
constrained manipulation all of this
completely zero shock just from text
input so you might be wondering how did
we get
here well that is going to be the focus
of today's
talk so let's start off with some
motivation let's watch this video of a
person opening a door and you'll see
that there's clearly two stages one in
which we reach a pre- contact pose in
this case the door handle and then
there's contact R interaction actually
turning the handle and pulling open the
door maybe we can use this idea to
decompose manipulation
tasks let's instantiate this by defining
a new policy class local policies as
policies that are initialized close to
the object of Interest or interaction
Point okay so let me pause here I mean
this is the same thing that I've been
pushing for a while which is the notion
of a skill which is at the unit of 1
second is also consistent with what we
know about how children learn so their
initi
phase is they reach but they cannot
grasp so if you see kids in their cribs
they they just their hands are flailing
about but they basically manage to reach
an object and then they push it or it
shakes or makes some noise or whatever
they're not ready yet to make grasps
that comes later so there's so they call
this in that in that literature it's
called The Reach phase followed by the
grip phase or the grasp phase so there
and we talked about it earlier in the
when we were discussing uh you know
insights from Child Development so this
breaking up into phases is very natural
uh and it so anyway let me
continue initial State distribution they
take in local observations just in the
vicinity of the object or interaction
point and take local actions in that
region AKA relative actions it looks
something like
this these local policies have some
great properties they're invariant to
Absolute Loop pose because they only
care about the relative positioning of
the hand at the object they're invariant
to skill ordering since we can use
motion planning to take care of the
chaining problem I'll talk about this in
more detail later and finally and most
importantly they're invariant to the
global scene configuration because they
only care about the local region around
the object okay so let me comment here
uh why do I like this so so what is that
condition do XE is about the end
effector and then the T right so it's
essentially you're going to you're going
to have a stage where you you get to the
the location where your hand needs to
operate on the object and then there's a
transport phase so now you've got
modularity so this modularity is what we
we did uh when we were doing uh uh
navigation right so you you can have
modularity you can have obstacle
avoidance dealt with by other methods
there many many techniques which you
will do obstacle avoidance classical
techniques and neural techniques I mean
so in that process you've got robustness
to the varieties of different scenes
that you can have because the rest of
the scene doesn't matter you get to the
object of interest and then you're are
going to do stuff with it like you can
maybe you're going to pick it maybe
you're going to throw it whatever okay
that comes at the end now these these
modular skills can be compos together
they're calling these skills local
policy but but I call them
skills okay this is not there are
challenges with this right because
sometimes the errors can accumulate and
what you need to do is that there needs
to be some preconditions which are
specified before you can execute a skill
but but uh a couple of years ago I had a
paper with dendra chaplot and a student
intern and hu which was uh which was was
essentially on how this composition of
skills can work you need to have you
need to when one skill ends and the
other skill begins you need to be in the
correct configuration that's the
condition that you have to do in which
and after that you can actually chain
together many
steps uh not just because chaining
always means that you're reducing your
probability of success but if you are
careful about this it can be done quite
well end to endend policies become uh
suffer from the combinatorial blowup
because now you have to train end to end
policies for all the exponentially many
combinations of skills that you have I
think where is when you train skills
then you get it just becomes linear in
the number of
skills okay mean it's much much simpler
to generate data for them at
scale the core idea of men of gen is
that these local policies enable us to
scale learning for manipulation in
simulation and transfer it to the real
world in a modular structure to solve a
wide variety of different
tasks as an overview of this work manip
first uses RL to acquire local behaviors
at scale then we distill these thousands
of experts into a single visual motor
policy per skill and then finally we
deploy these policies zero shot in
challenging environments by using a VM
to plan motion planner to reach poses
near objects and local policies to for
manipulation so how do actually acquire
local behaviors using RL well for the
observations we found it important to
include a significant amount of
privileged information in this phase
which we do so by incorporating shape
information and components of the reward
for the reward itself we have a general
formulation that looks something like
this here re R obge and R success
specify the behavior of the skill while
the other two rewards constrain the
motion of the policy making it easier to
transfer s to
real now putting everything together we
pass the privileged and prop receptive
State information into the policy and we
train these policies using po at
scale okay to see our local policies in
action check out okay let me let me
pause there and and okay uh let me
comment here so if you uh good example
uh to think about this is the work we
had on Ro rotating objects so I think I
we talked about this earlier how's work
and tooru's work rotating objects what
do we need for that you need to know
something about the shape of the object
right and and this is something which at
execution time is going to be estimated
with the help of cameras or cameras plus
touch or cameras plus touch plus
proception I mean so my claim here is
trust perception perception can do
something perception computer vision
people are not idiots they have are able
to achieve some goals and they can pull
something out okay when you do training
what do you do we this idea of
privileged information is a very useful
one and this has been very successful in
Locomotion so the version of that here
is that you have some some low
dimensional representation of the shape
so maybe you have the shape and then you
run it through some Auto encoder or
something which makes it lower
dimensional and you feed that generally
speaking uh motor policies like
manipulation or Locomotion they do not
need exactly all the details of the
environment underneath your feet they do
not need exactly all the details of the
shape of the object there's an
approximation of the shape which is good
enough from which you can act and that's
what you you want to capture right you
can do that at training time then it's
privileged information at test time
you're going to rely on your sensing
from vision touch proception to to to do
the best job possible so this philosophy
we saw earlier in the work of rotating
objects or un you know removing lids and
so on you you you see a version of
exactly that same idea here so this is a
robust idea I mean let me say I like
this idea a lot okay let's keep playing
Y at
scale and always we just see our local
policies in action check out these
videos of the pick Place grasp handle
articulated object opening and closing
skills for pick and place we sample
random clutter and distractor objects
and encourage the agent to only interact
with the target object here shown in red
one thing to really emphasize here is
that due to locality we can make the
simulation environments dead simple but
we can still generalize to complex real
world
scenarios the reason this is possible is
that we are in variant to Global scene
configurations since we only observe
things
locally now that we've acquired behavior
we need to distill all of these single
task experts into a single generalist
policy per skill the key to doing this
is using online imitation learning since
ourl policies can give us dense feedback
at any state they're queriable experts
so we can just do multitask dagger now
for the observations we opt to use wrist
camera observations which which are of
course local once the policy gets super
close to the object it might have some
difficulty in telling what's going on so
we also incorporate the first frame
which generally has a clear view of the
object we also need to communicate Which
object to interact with so we pass in a
segmentation mask of the target object
which we can easily get in the real
world using grounded Sam now for local
policies we found that you actually
don't need an enormous sequence model to
fit the data really well so here we opt
for resonet 18 based AR chitecture with
a spatial softmax at the end and then we
use an MLP decoder to predict Delta and
Defector control actions and just train
with Ms Loss using yeah so I mean this
part feels similar right you've got
cameras and so on but there is a
specific thing of using computer vision
in a more sophisticated way so they are
using grounded Sam so computer vision
techniques for segmenting objects
labeling objects there's no reason to do
everything end to end I mean in the
previous lecture you saw everything was
being done end to end so as if the only
Vision which you need to learn is in the
context of this task whereas what this
is saying is hey there is all this work
that the computer vision Community has
done let's make you use of it
okay
dagger so now the question becomes how
do we actually deploy these visual motor
local policies in the real world
for that we build on prior work on plan
sequence learn which used a hierarchical
decomposition to efficiently train
specialist policies or challenging
manipulation tasks a quick
sidebar PSL uses an llm to decompose the
task specified via natural language into
a course high level plan it then uses
vision and motion planning to actually
step through the plan which is done by
estimating the pose of the target object
and then motion planning to it finally
it uses RL policies to efficiently learn
local yeah so let me pause here I mean
again I think this is this is the idea
of a hierarchy right as opposed to just
end to end learning of every for every
task there's a hierarchy here the
hierarchy is very sensible at the
highest levels of the hierarchy you use
language language is great for capturing
goals and substeps of plans then we are
trying to get to substeps of plans this
is where Vision comes in because the
substeps of plans will typically involve
you know poses and how you interact with
an object and different poses you'll
interact with in a different way so your
sort of computer vision 3D all of that
kind of stuff comes into this this stage
and then there is the actual motor
policy and uh here instead of just
designing it we are going to try to
learn it we can use different ways of
learning it which we can use uh I mean
you know there's nothing wrong with
supervision but in this case uh uh this
once the task becomes simple enough uh
reinforcement learning is a good
approach and reinforcement learning uh
the value why why I like that is because
uh robustness and generalization can in
some sense be built in because you can
you can put in noise you can have
different kinds of shapes etc etc so so
you so so the scaling law I mean you
need diversity but that diversity here
is in the training environment
we not relying on the diversity oper
coming from the human
teleoperators interaction however this
is all done in the loop to learn a
specific
task the core challenge now is moving
from The Specialist approach to a
generalist approach for
manipulation for each step we will use
learning at scale to build generalist
with specialized capabilities and then
combine them to massively amplify their
generalization first to perform real
world task planning we need the agent to
perceive the environment which requires
the use of some sort of a VM instead of
an llm here we use GPT 40 as we found
that VMS trained on internet scale data
perform quite well next for fast
reactive real world motion plan we want
to use a motion planner that can operate
on noisy Point Cloud input here we use
neural motion planner and endtoend
policy for performing fast motion
planning in the real world finally we
come to the core new piece of of manip
gen which I just described to train
generalists that can solve new tasks in
a zero chop manner we need pre-trained
skills which we obtain by scaling up
learning in simulation and transferring
Sim to
real having defined all of these
components let's quickly walk through an
example deployment here we use the VM to
come up with a plan for the scene given
views of the scene and text
prompt it comes up with a plan in terms
of the skill Library using the
formatting I show here we then deploy
this plan open loop estimating where to
go using ground to segment the target
object Point Cloud averaging it to get a
position and I I have to repeat my
claiming that skills these are the
essential uh component so here if you
see all of these are skills so it's open
and these are that's a skill pick is a
skill place is a skill close is a skill
and then these skills are parameterized
because they have to do something
different for each object so open handle
pick rice and so on
so the basic components of Human Action
are there is a subject verb object the
subject is the agent me the human the
verb is like open or pick and then there
is an object on which I'm acting and
sometimes there can be two objects
because there is a tool and then there
is something you're operating on this is
the basic vocabulary of action this is
the basic vocabulary with which to
interpret video streams this is the
basic vocabulary with which to act in
the world it's pretty it's it's common
sense I mean to me this is not rocket
size but wal said that common sense is
very uncommon okay so let me continue
Collision free poses that point at the
object we alternate between pose
estimation neural MP and running the
right local policy until the task is
solved okay let's quickly look at some
results we evaluate manip on five
different diverse tasks achieving High
success rates across each task at least
60% on the hardest long Horizon tasks
with up to 90% on some challenging
multi-stage manipulation tasks like
storing items in the cabinet our tasks
are extremely challenging requiring the
agent to perform pick in place
articulated object manipulation
constrained tight space manipulation all
of this entirely zero shot from text
prompts we evaluate using a diverse
object set varying the objects to
manipulate and the receptacles for every
task with strong pose randomization to
ensure that really stress testing minip
gen's generalization capabilities note
we did not directly train on any of the
objects we evaluate on instead by
training local manipulation at scale
manip is able to generalize
broadly so compare this to Aloha
Unleashed where the training is on
exactly the objects that they will be
manipulating in terms of numerical
results we show that our method beats
out some very relevant baselines in
terms of text condition manipulation
we include the succcess rate per task as
well as the average number of stages
completed essentially logging the
average progress along the task we also
have more results in the paper with
comparisons and simulation as well as
more real world tasks comparing against
end to end RL BC task and motion
planning and more okay let me stop here
but I mean some of these are quite
famous and well-known systems open vaa
Sean Etc so I I haven't gone into the
details of are these comparisons
actually Fair and you can judge that for
yourself I I I passed no judgment on
that but at least going by this table
it's pretty it's pretty impressive and
as I said this approach is not rocket
science to me this is obviously the one
that we should do it's like the
straightforward thing right uh it's not
the complicated thing it's the
straightforward thing okay based
planning methods and with that I thank
you for listening and for additional
detail including videos experimental
setups and implementation details please
check out our website linked on the left
and read our Twitter summary on the
right
okay uh so let's go back
to uh this and uh okay so that was the
cover and uh let me go to
the to the so we can look at this
further so what are the St stages uh
essentially uh learn I mean the the
heavy work is being done by ARL right RL
is providing so you are you pick you're
developing skills for picking up for
different kinds of shapes of objects so
that is being done by RN right and uh
and then and so forth and it should not
be just pickup it should be other skills
as well so the what's what can you
imagine as a generalization of this so
here there are only a few skills pick up
place open handle and so on so the set
of skills demonstrated here are far
fewer than you saw in the in the work
from Google or the work from uh from
PI
okay what I think so so so just grant
them that if we are
comparing you know apples it's comparing
apples to oranges so the range of skills
here is far limited however in my view
they meet these two criteria of
generalization and
robustness in much better I'm more
satisfied with that uh I I like the
overall hierarchical structure of this
because I don't think we can solve uh
large scale robotics problems without
having some notion of
hierarchy okay I think they use language
model in the right way I mean often some
of the there is work which use uses llms
for the lowest level stuff of you know
joint angles that to me is not doesn't
make sense uh but using language for the
higher levels of planning is totally
sensible okay I mean there could be
versions on on that theme some uh there
are some versions where you generate a
program and and execute I mean all of
that is fine I think the way where they
have used uh GPT for like in terms of
visual recognition where they've used
grounded samp these are all I mean you
can try this or that you know those are
all choices that people might make
differently but that seems sensible uh
so let me uh let me uh they have a slide
which is
on
uh uh I think this is the one which has
the Bold numbers and I I don't want to
stand by this because I'm not uh you
know actually read the paper carefully
enough to see whether I believe the uh
the that this experiment has been done
carefully but at least the claim here is
quite bold because there is like a small
team doing something as opposed to a big
machine so let's let's discuss this for
a bit I if I have time we may go into
talking about the line of work from
Nvidia which has also consistently there
they have a series of papers which are
in the simulation Paradigm with ARL and
I think that work is to be taken
seriously uh but I I started with this
paper because it's like one
paper uh to read and one talk to listen
to but let's do discussion
first comments opinions
criticisms
yeah yeah yeah so so the generalization
is coming at the skill level
at the higher level it's sort of there
vanilla thing which people 50 years
would ago would have said you're going
to have little some operators and you're
going to chain them together in some
plant I mean that that is no I mean
doing it with llms is the current way of
doing it but all the generalization is
happening at the a lot of at the
individual skill level so when I pick up
an object I manage to pick it up
whatever the object is and whatever the
Clutter is
yeah
number
example
ex
open Open Door
no no no no no let's take that example
so I would argue that I mean and and
this is for everybody for this approach
the previous approach right this is
essentially that when you are executing
things can happen that you had not
anticipated okay how do you deal with
that and uh I would have to give that
Partyline answer for both approaches the
Partyline answer for the tell
operation with uh has to be okay well if
we run this these operate T operations a
million times then those kinds of Errors
will also occur and we will deal with
them and then we will have that in our
training data the simulation people have
to say the same thing which is that when
I'm when I'm doing the task uh I I'm
going to perturb in various ways and and
those perturbations are going to provide
the diversity so both have to give the
same answer I'm not sure I mean and both
of these in theory can deal with it but
in practice how will it works I don't
know yeah
t they don't
[Music]
they talk about for
example for and they
use very
goodia that's like know zero any
environment doogers they're heavily
relying on other people like Innovations
withall
doogers no
no no but let me stop you there that to
me is not a bug it's a feature I think
that uh I think that there's this line
from Newton only reason I've seen
further than others is because I've
stood on the shoulders of giants okay
and the old joke goes it's better to
stand on the shoulders of giants than to
stand on the toes of their feet right
okay so then to step on their toes right
so so if you can find a way to use
uh modules that have been trained with a
huge amount of data by other people I
mean it could be real data it could be
simulation that to me is a positive
thing yeah so I mean it may be that it
diminishes the Delta of this paper
that's okay but but but I don't regard
using a pre-trained module as a negative
thing I think to me that's neutral if at
the end you get the job done better
great okay
multiply like the P by the like local
policy what I was saying is like why
don't you just reach and then activate
cont there are already a lot of really
good models of doogers that have beening
on the
okay
[Music]
isent as they're using like G
more fair if they pluged in G and like
any other Vision stuff like thats and
cook are effectively just like
industrial bin placings right where the
bin for cook is like your big that they
put like corn
[Music]
orever that's
get 20% that doesn't really make much
sense to me you could use so many like
older in like years their hardest I
don't really understand these numbers
and then like in terms of the setup like
they have like five cam right like they
have the camera from which they use for
like activating the local policy because
they have this whole like ination on how
important the size of that local CR is
and then they have every corner and the
reason why they Excel so much in like
these that have the sh and like
replin because motion neur
wasur the method I'm not convinced by
I'm not convinced by the they don't very
using way more advanced and language I
think you just replace like
especially they do a lot of
articul just the
way on the articula object different
ofas right they also deal open and like
that you just use simar Environ what
they have and like
ret work well set these
experiment
neur I see okay so so I think you made a
couple of different points so let me
unpack them so one is specifically about
this comparison to other work which as I
said I don't want to defend because I
did not read and uh your critique May
well be quite correct it's a it's a
standard it's a it's a it's a challenge
really so what I want to bring up from
that is like the challenge of doing
robotics work because uh in computer
vision when we do comparisons we we have
exactly the same data set so with which
so you're you take your new technique
you run it I mean it's exactly the same
data set here you have if you want to do
experiments in the real world now you
you're getting the class of scenes that
these folks are considering are
different from the class of scenes that
Vox posa was con which is different from
the class of scenes that Sean was coning
so us essentially have these uh domain
shifts in the lab setup and and those
are favoring one approach or the other
so I I mean this's like a there's like
a a scientific replicability problem
that bevil's robotics
research I mean it's true I mean okay uh
then uh the there was this issue of uh
what uh like like uh how much juice was
there in their skills right essentially
and uh uh that that there were uh there
were
pre-trained quote uh sort of foundation
models of skills like right like
something for grasping whatever that can
do 99% of the work and and uh maybe what
they added was very little now that's a
that's a good point so that they should
really have address by doing suitable
ablation studies because that I can see
that there's an experimental uh you can
do an experiment with that you can do
exactly you can just see how much did I
gain from using my RL policy versus what
I would have by just taking a
previous previous approach so this is a
very uh very valid
point there's a third point which you
made about experimental evaluation which
is a critique which is true
of both work across which is that uh we
run these experiments comparing to some
older paper and in the meanwhile many
things have improved and your paper has
all those new fangled things and that
old paper has all the old stuff so maybe
you're you're using a much more powerful
llm maybe you're using a much powerful
segmentor maybe you're using a much
powerful more powerful recognition
engine Etc
and and this is a challenge also for
computer vision systems so there were
there were some uh there was a very nice
paper from Serge bongi at all which was
on this task of metric learning where
people had been writing papers for years
and they all of course to be published
they were better than the previous
year's papers so what what they did was
they just reimplemented all those papers
but using the most modern techniques for
how to train a network the size of the
network the augmentations ETC and then
they found that all those approaches
were equivalent so there was there was
an older paper which was simpler and
which actually worked as well okay and
this is sadly true okay because uh
what's happening over time is that uh we
we we get we we improve many different
aspects we improve our data
augmentations we improve how we
initialize our neural network we improve
our training recipes all of this right
so therefore the experiments are never
in comparable conditions and and maybe
there is an aspect of that here yeah so
this is this casts uh some concern yeah
continue didn't this but that's like and
false they didn't in in terms of like
every time they would decide to go from
one stage to the next what the plan they
wouldn't they were successful
but the perception was Clos because they
do mention that like ground has issued
so they would back ground
outut
the which okay right like that helps a
lot too yeah yeah no but but but those
are quote hacks which I I regard as
legit right maybe they maybe they they
they should have been more honest in
stating that
but I regard those as legitimate because
those are scalable presumably you could
do that every
time
okay okay that's fair
uh uh more comments other
comments yeah
how
objects okay okay so 's question is how
do you test the generalization of scales
yeah so for me the test is many many
different objects so I I mean my good
example of this is the the paper we had
with howy he's rotating objects and he
rotates like you know they all I mean we
we could not have rotated an object
which was like a one foot basketball or
something right the basket balls are not
one foot but a one foot Globe we
couldn't have done that because in the
hand that doesn't fit but of objects of
the size which is something like 5 cm by
5 cm by 5 cm in this kind of Zone we
tried many many different objects and it
worked across them so I think that to me
that's a requirement I mean you're doing
a robotic skill it should work across
many different objects or many different
sizes and shapes and friction properties
and so
onas AUP or
open no no they're not exactly the same
so there will be so it's like but when
we are recognizing dogs we have many
different breeds of
dogs so in fact the operation of say
pushing an object pushing an object if
the object is very heavy pushing an
object is very different than when
pushing a small object on a des drop so
so in our language in the English
language and in other human languages we
use
verbs which with which are with a very
with a great amount of generalization
inbuilt into the definition of the verb
so there's generalization with nouns too
right because dogs I mean it's a
category there are many many different
kinds of dogs and different poses and
everything else but when we consider
verbs like insert or push or
throw there can be many different
physical ways of doing it so just like
the pixels are not the same for
different kinds of dogs the motor
actions are not going to be the same for
different kinds of throw different kinds
of insert and so on but we must
generalize I think this is this is what
we believe to be to be important and and
true right we must show how to
generalize
more questions or
comments okay so let's uh I have how
much time do I have I have like seven
minutes I want to uh go and spend a few
minutes on that uh Nvidia website
because I think that's gives you another
flavor of this line of work so uh okay
to just close out on this paper
I never pay very much attention to the
details I think the important thing
always is the overall philosophy if I
like the overall philosophy that's what
I'm trying to convey here I like the
overall philosophy of this paper all the
details will change next year we'll find
a different way of doing each of these
things but you know there's a quote from
uh uh Tuki which I'll I'll I'll St so
Tiki was the STA station he's one of the
co-inventors of the fast Foria transform
he says better and approximate solution
to the right problem then the exact
solution to the wrong
problem okay I believe in this so if you
are kind of working up the right tree
and you have something which doesn't
work super well but it's sort of hitting
the most important components in kind of
the right way I'm much
more I I I like that much more because
then I feel okay one year later 2 years
later 3 years later there'll be more
work and it'll get better but if you are
fundamentally wrongheaded okay then uh
what's not worth doing is not worth
doing with great detail and more data
okay so I am just stating my
philosophical biases here okay so this
is a Nvidia blog p they have a series of
papers before this and this is uh this
is one of uh I think the last paper in
this series and there are earlier papers
and toru can add more details because
she has hung out with these people so
they they took this problem which I like
okay so this is the problem of
insertion okay but they're not like
taking this uh Aloha Unleashed and doing
it for one particular assembly they
trying to do it for all of these so in
all of these there is some part which
has to be inserted into some other part
so they call this the plug and the
socket so the plug is what gets inserted
into the socket and then they have all
these different shapes so there's the
white bit and there's the green bit and
one of them the white bit has to be
inserted into the green bit okay so
before I proceed what do you think they
would have
done what do you think they should have
done you already have some hints you
know that they are into simulation okay
simulation makes a lot of use of Nvidia
chips okay they are into RL okay so what
should you
do so you have to do okay so this paper
is called
automate okay so okay so what are their
contributions you can probably see this
a data set of 100 assemblies and ready
to use simulation environments and then
they train policies for these 100
different tasks so you can guess what it
should be right we always know that RL
works better when you have access to
privileged information what you really
want to say is RL works better when the
space is is reduced so when the space is
smaller then you're doing trial ER eror
in that space and then you come up with
the right policy so in narrower spaces
it's much easier to to get success with
RL and then we can train all those and
then we can this distance them together
into one policy that's a reasonable
strategy okay I I mean that's what you
would expect them to employ right okay
so uh let's see what they do so
deployment of Auto let me automate
assembly skills and
simulation data sets and simulation what
did they do they provide a data set of
100 assemblies and 3D printable objects
as well as parallelized simulation
environments for all 100 assemblies they
are based on a large assembly data set
from
Autodesk and then they have plugs and
sockets so this is the picture example
of a single environment and then you
have zillions of these going on in
simulation okay learning Specialists
over diverse geometry so you can call
these Specialists so this idea is not
that different from what you saw in the
previous one in fact you also have that
when we have our walking work because we
have privileged information and then we
have this Z which is sort of learn with
which you're learning different
strategies for different uh terrains
right uh generating de so what do we
need generating demonstration for
assembly integration integrating an
imitation learning objective into RL
selecting demonstrations to use during
learning okay here's a cute trick though
it's not I it's not doesn't work fully
but uh assembly is hard but disassembly
is
easy right so assembly is like putting
things together you need to get their
tolerances right disassembly is easy you
can every every kid knows how to break
things but not how to build things so
disassembly is easy and then you just
run it in reverse so you've got a
trajectory so this is cute right okay
but it may not be right in terms of
being a robust way to do it but at least
you get trajectories so uh and by the
way this should remind you of diffusion
models diffusion models uh you know as
you diffuse and add noise It Go becomes
like it's like you can't you don't know
what it's just meaningless but then you
can run it in reverse because every
micro step every small step in a
diffusion process is reversible so so I
I I I had not thought of this before so
when I read this paper I said oh yeah
obviously
this is
cool uh okay but there are there this
may not necessarily lead to robust
strategies for assembly but still it's I
think it's cute okay and you can think
about this in other
settings right RL with an imitation
objective okay uh so there uh what do
they do they basically have humans do
the task so we like that but this is
visual limitation humans do the task
and then uh so this is there's a human
task and then we want to put this on a
robot so these are standard tricks
Dynamic time warping you have one
trajectory another trajectory you want
to align them you you do Dynamic time
warping this is like a classical idea it
originated in the speech Community I
think they probably papers on it from
1960s or 70s so they do that for
aligning trajectory so so take human
demonstrations and use that
to initialize your
RM so that seems okay then they so now
they've generated these specialist
policies so they actually land up
generating 100 different policies for
100 different assemblies okay and they
get I and then I what I was uh I found
was compelling they do this in
simulation then they repeat the
experiment in real and the numbers are
reasonably consistent so this is good
right because one of our challenges in
robotics is how do we do experiments how
do we know whether our work is good and
simulation is much easier and much more
replicable but your simulation results
may have nothing to do with real world
results and here they give a fairly
compelling example that they are they
give you some flavor of what is
happening in the real
world then we come to the task of
learning a general assembly skill okay
what do you expect this to be
essentially what you expect is I mean
again don't have to read the paper just
think about it and you'll know what
they're going to do I mean they're going
to try to use distillation they're going
to have dagger in there somewhere okay
once you think about it for 10 minutes
after that you should go and read the
paper and you'll find that they've done
more or less those things this by the
way is a good device so let me give you
this graus as advice for research
Whenever there is some topic that you
don't know that much about uh you you
you you you read the paper you start the
paper you read the first part of it
maybe the introduction understand to
which is stating the problem right and
now you shut the paper up okay you go
off and you think about it yourself
spend an hour thinking about how you
would solve the problem okay and it may
be that for most of many papers you may
find that you actually find the solution
that they find sometimes you may not
sometimes you might find another
solution some but very importantly what
you will find are what are the difficult
aspects of the problem when you try to
struggle with it yourself without
looking at the
solution and this is a this is a trick
which when did I learn like 45 years ago
from Donald K one of the founders of
computer science said whenever he any
area he he doesn't he doesn't read the
solution he first reads the problem
statement he tries to work it out
himself after he has tried to work it
out then he reads the solution so this
is a good uh good research advice okay
anyway I think that if you did that you
will find that what they've done is
quite sensible so uh so they've got uh a
set of policies be behavior and then
they use dagger which is always the
right way to think about robustification
because when you are proceeding on some
you executing some policy things will
happen which are unexpected and you'll
go off the path and you need to recover
and that recovery this comes very
naturally from all the simulation
data so anyway then they get this
generalist policy whose performance
decreases a bit but not too bad and then
there is blah blah on how they did it
which I will leave because I'm already
six minutes over time so thank you very
much okay
uh